Sean Bannon

17908 Gottschalk Ave. Homewood, IL 60430 708-408-7177 Seannbannon@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

I've obtained five years of experience in the customer service sector, dealing with environmental services, e-commerce retail, maintenance and education. My gregarious personality, customer-first mentality, and strong work ethic makes it easy to meet and exceed customer's expectations with a service that sells more products. I thrive in a constantly changing environment and am looking for a position where I can hone my communication skills.

SKILLS

- Excellent verbal and written communication
- Proficient multitasker and effective creative problem solver
- Team management
- Staff training
- Project organization
- MS Office
- Google Spreadsheets

EXPERIENCE

The Nature Conservancy, Karlstad, MN - Land Steward

April 2019 - October 2019

- Involved in <20000 acres of controlled burns in various positions
- Help restore the Tall Grass prairie (one of the rarest Ecosystems in the world) using different methods.
- Treating invasive plants chemically as well as mechanically.
- Collected seeds and classified different types of plants based on makeup.
- Restored land using machinery such as ATV and Tractor.

Kelly Staffing, Michigan City, IN - Substitute Teacher

November 2018- April 2019

- Follow curriculum by guiding and engaging students of different backgrounds and intellectual levels to support their successes.
- Identify and defuse escalating predicaments for quick and fair resolution.
- Provide full attention to student's input and assess their knowledge with empathy to create a rewarding experience.

Dunes National Lakeshore, Porter, IN - Custodial

June 2018- October 2018

• Working for the Department of the Interior at West Beach doing general custodial work and maintenance. Drive ATV, trim grasses, etc. Prioritized projects for each day's needs.

Amazon, Monee, IL - Process Guide

November 2017- March 2018

Worked diligently with the team to pack shipments with correct products and shipping

labels.

Quickly promoted 1 month after hire to Process Guide after becoming top packer, where I
individually monitored, motivates, and assisted other coworkers to package shipments to
meet deadlines.

Uber / Wag, IL - Dog Walker

July 2017- Present

Self-motivated by providing on-demand service via phone applications. Drive experience
with memorable warmth and personality. Implemented quick decision making regarding
routes and responding to issues appropriately.

Dominos Pizza, Homewood, IL - Delivery Driver

November 2016- May 2017

 Deliver pizzas, customer service, assist with opening and closing stores, food prep, phones etc.

The Nature Conservancy, Merrillville, IN – Conservation Crew

April 2016 - October 2016

- Worked in a group setting, eradicating invasive plants
- Conducted ecological surveys of the land i.e. Frog and Butterfly
- Collect and plant native seeds in a greenhouse as well as in the field

Homewood Park District, Homewood, IL - Building Supervisor

December 2015 - May 2016

- Managed event logistics in the banquet hall. Communicated rules and ensured compliance. Dealt with problems as they arose with precision and professionalism.
- Helped to hire several employees.
- Guided guests around location and
- Coordinated and broke down spaces after events.

Securitas, East Chicago, IN - Security Officer

October 2014 - May 2015

• On-site security officer responsible for vehicle inspections, issuing on-site security passes, general overall compliance and safety for visitors to the steel mill.

Home City Ice, Crown Point, IN - Seasonal Driver

May 2014 - August 2014

- Delivered ice on the assigned route. Full time position over the summer. Very physically demanding.
- Negotiated with business owners for sales.

Jewel Osco, Homewood, IL - Cashier

April 2011 - September 2013

 Answer customer questions and complaints, stocked shelves, and processed customer purchases.

EDUCATION

Purdue Calumet, Hammond, IN - Human Resources Management, BA

Prairie State Community College, Chicago Heights, IL - Liberal Arts, AA